<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marco Kwak</title>
    <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marco Kwak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 18:55:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloud.marcokwak.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Need for Your Own Homelab?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/what-do-you-need-for-your-own-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/what-do-you-need-for-your-own-homelab/</guid>
      <description>What is Homelab? I have used many public cloud services for a while. Since I started my career as a software engineer, AWS was already quite popular. Some old developer folks might not have chance to use public cloud services when landing on their first job, but I was lucky. So I used AWS in my first company. I have used AWS, GCP, Firebase for most of my careers.
But I always wanted to have my own home data center, which is a homelab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Era of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/the-era-of-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:05:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/the-era-of-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>What is a Computer? We all know what a computer is, but at the same time most of us do not know what a computer is. We just use computers on a daily basis and know how to use it. But it is not easy to say that we know how it works.
A computer consists of CPU(s), RAM(s), Storage(s), Network device(s).
CPUs are for calculation. For example, if you open up an MS Excel file and run some functions in it, then your file requests CPU resource to perform the task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I start this blog?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/why-do-i-start-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 06:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/why-do-i-start-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been writing articles in my Korean blog for a while. Thanks to those who read, my first book was published 2 years back. I always wanted to start writing technical articles in English for wider range of audiences from all over the world. And today, it finally came to action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Marco</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/about/</guid>
      <description>A solutions and software engineer, currently working for VMware.
I am into Cloud technologies, especially Hybrid Cloud and DevOps:
 Hybrid Cloud &amp;amp; Multi Cloud Kubernetes CI/CD  Passionate About Business and Numbers I have run a couple of businesses when working as a software engineer for 6+ years.
 Online Coding Education Platform IT Consulting  And this is why I decided to become a solutions engineer. I always wanted to have a wider view of business, but as a software engineer, I always felt the chance was very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>