<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marco Kwak</title>
    <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marco Kwak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 19:28:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prepare CKA and CKAD</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/how-to-prepare-cka-and-ckad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 19:28:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/how-to-prepare-cka-and-ckad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Data Center Edition Comparison</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-nsx-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 20:17:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-nsx-edition/</guid>
      <description>What is NSX Data Center? You always use Network to access to the Internet. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go to a place without Internet connection like an island, you are technically living with Networks; Wifi, mobile cellular data, routers to provide wifi at home, etc.
But I had not thought of Network as a computing resource before joining VMware. Even my previous company was one of wireless network hardware vendor, Ruckus Network, but my exposure to Networking was limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSAN Edition Comparison</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-vsan-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 20:02:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-vsan-edition/</guid>
      <description>What is vSAN? Have you heard of HCI, Hyper Converged Infrastructure? It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I joined VMware. I still feel that the term HCI is too fancy and not very intuitive. But it is not a fault of VMware because VMware is not the one who invented the term.
Hyper Converged Infrastructure usually means server computers with internal shared storages. What? When we use a laptop or a desktop, it usually comes with storage inside, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Edition Comparison</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-vsphere-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:15:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/vmware-products-vsphere-edition/</guid>
      <description>What is vSphere? I believe that you already know what vSphere is if you visit this post. Since VMware vSphere is the most popular server virtualization product, so if you are in the IT infrastructure industry, you must have heard of vSphere once at leat. But just in case someone visits this blog to learn about VMware and its products, I would like to describe what vSphere is.
Before talking about what vSphere is, we need to know what a hypervisor is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Need for Your Own Homelab?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/what-do-you-need-for-your-own-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/what-do-you-need-for-your-own-homelab/</guid>
      <description>What is Homelab? I have used many public cloud services for a while. Since I started my career as a software engineer, AWS was already quite popular. Some old developer folks might not have chance to use public cloud services when landing on their first job, but I was lucky. So I used AWS in my first company. I have used AWS, GCP, Firebase for most of my careers.
But I always wanted to have my own home data center, which is a homelab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Era of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/the-era-of-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:05:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/the-era-of-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>What is a Computer? We all know what a computer is, but at the same time most of us do not know what a computer is. We just use computers on a daily basis and know how to use it. But it is not easy to say that we know how it works.
A computer consists of CPU(s), RAM(s), Storage(s), Network device(s).
CPUs are for calculation. For example, if you open up an MS Excel file and run some functions in it, then your file requests CPU resource to perform the task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do I Start This Blog?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/why-do-i-start-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 06:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.marcokwak.com/posts/why-do-i-start-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been writing articles in my Korean blog for a while. Thanks to those who read, my first book was published 2 years back. I always wanted to start writing technical articles in English for wider range of audiences from all over the world. And today, it finally came to action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>